A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Field Offices, Paris, RG 6, SG 1 FA395
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Post-war, 1945-1959; 2; 81 Boxes; 42 cubic feet
  - Post-war - Correspondence, 01
    - DMPH United States, 1949-1955 (Box 60, Folder 544)
      Hiscock, Ira Vaughan - (travel, public health) - 1954-1955 Keys, Ancel - (physiology) - 1949-1954 Makover, Henry B. - (travel, preventive medicine) - 1952-1954
    - DMPH United States - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 60, Folder 545)
      Edwards, Phyllis Q. - (public health) - 1954 Fox, Renee - (social psychology) - 1954 Kastens, Merril - (visit) - 1954 Russell, John R. - (neurosurgery) - 1954
    - DMPH United States, 1950-1956 (Box 60, Folder 546)
      Silver, George A. - (public health) - 1950-1955 Thomas, Harold A. - (travel, sanitary engineering) - 1955-1956 Thomas, Lewis - (travel, pediatrics) - 1953-1955 Willard, Howard Nelson - (preventive medicine) - 1953-1954
    - DMPH Wales - Cardiff City Mental Hospital, 1952-1957 (Box 60, Folder 547)
    - DMPH Wales, 1952-1954 (Box 60, Folder 548)
      Declinations - Brotmacher, Leon - (physiology) - 1954 Declinations - Dodgson, K.S. and Spencer, B. - (physiology) - 1952 Miscellaneous - Watkins, A.G. - (pediatrics) - 1953
    - DMPH West Africa - Gadan University College - Medical Faculty, 1942-1954 (Box 60, Folder 549)
    - DMPH Yugoslavia, 1952-1955 (Box 60, Folder 550)
      Bujevic, Aldo - (nutrition) - 1952-1954 Cmelik, S. - (declination, hygiene) - 1953-1955
    - DMPH Yugoslavia - Declinations, 1953-1955 (Box 60, Folder 551)
      Golubovic, Djordje - (engineering) - 1953 Junger, Georg - (psychology) - 1953-1954 Mihailovic, Ljubodrag - (neurophysiology) - 1953-1955 Petrovitch, Dr. - (ophthalmology) - 1953
    - DMPH Yugoslavia, 1950-1955 (Box 60, Folder 552)
      Grcevic, Nenad - (neuropathology) - 1952 Gurski, Ferdo - (declination, public health) - 1951-1952 Hauptfeld, Richard - (physiology) - 1950-1952 Ivekovic, Hrvoje - (travel, industrial hygiene) - 1950-1955
    - DMPH Yugoslavia, 1946-1955 (Box 60, Folder 553)
      Kesic, Branco M. - (industrial hygiene) - 1946-1947, 1951-1955 Ljubljana Institute of Pathologie - Physiology - 1952 Ljubljana University - Faculty of Medicine - 1947-1952 Maic, Danielo - (sanitary engineering) - 1951-1953 Mesing, Danila - (nursing) - 1949-1953 Meskovic, Milutin - (declination, physiology) - 1947-1952
    - DMPH Yugoslavia - Miscellaneous, 1952-1954 (Box 61, Folder 554)
      Fugas, Mirka - (industrial hygiene) - 1952 Gajic, Slobodan - (bacteriology) - 1954 Giaja, Jean - (physiology) - 1952 Guelminu, Georg - (malariology) - 1952 Kostic, Durhan - (public health) - no date Malina, Stevan - (neurosurgery) - 1953 Rapic, Smaie - (endocrinology) - 1953 Tolicic, Ivan - (psychology) - 1953
    - DMPH Yugoslavia, 1946-1956 (Box 61, Folder 555)
      Nursing - 1946-1953 Paukovik, Nikola - (travel, sanitary engineering) - 1950-1951 Rozensweig, Arnulf - (declination, neuro-psychiatry) - 1952-1953 Sarajevo Institute of Hygiene - 1952-1953 Sarvan, Milevoy - (declination, pediatrics) - 1948-1956
    - DMPH Yugoslavia - Zagreb Postgraduate School of Nursing (Box 61, Folder 556)
    - DMPH Yugoslavia - Zagreb University, 1946-1957 (Box 61, Folder 557)
      Faculty of Medicine - 1952-1956 Institute of Anatomy - 1952 Institute of Clinical Endocrinology - 1946-1952 Institute of Industrial Hygiene - 1951-1955 Institute of Pharmacology - 1946-1957
    - DMPH General - African Trips - (Logan, John, A.), 1951-1953 (Box 61, Folder 558)
    - DMPH General - All-Scandinavian School of Public Health, 1952-1956 (Box 61, Folder 559)
    - DMPH General - American Joint Distribution Committee, 1948-1954 (Box 61, Folder 560)
    - DMPH General - Books: Environmental Sanitation and Engineering, 1952-1955 (Box 61, Folder 561)
    - DMPH General - European Conferences for Sanitary Engineers, 1951-1952 (Box 61, Folder 562)
    - DMPH General - European Conferences for Sanitary Engineers, 1953-1954 (Box 62, Folder 563)
    - DMPH General - European Medical Schools, 1951-1953 (Box 62, Folder 564)
      Bachmeyer, A.C. - Report - 1951 Arthur C. Bachmeyer Memorial Lecture - 1953
    - DMPH General - European Symposia on Medical Education, 1951-1953 (Box 62, Folder 565)
      Vevey - 1952 Nice - 1953
    - DMPH General - Exchange Program, 1951-1953 (Box 62, Folder 566)
    - DMPH General - Hilton Read Program - (exchange of doctors), 1952-1954 (Box 62, Folder 567)
    - DMPH General - Human Ecology, 1950-1953 (Box 62, Folder 568)
    - DMPH General - International Children's Centre, 1948-1958 (Box 62, Folder 569)
    - DMPH General - International Children's Centre - Documents (10), 1950-1957 (Box 62, Folder 570)
    - DMPH General - International Conference on Regional Planning and Development, 1955 (Box 62, Folder 571)
    - DMPH General - International Council of Nurses and Florence Nightingale International Foundation, 1951-1955 (Box 62, Folder 572)
    - DMPH General - International Federation of Public Health and Preventive Medicine, 1951-1957 (Box 62, Folder 573)
    - DMPH General - International Union for Health Education, 1951-1956 (Box 62, Folder 574)
    - DMPH General - League of Red Cross Societies, 1952-1955 (Box 62, Folder 575)
    - DMPH General - London Office for Sanitary Engineering, 1951-1956 (Box 62, Folder 576)
    - DMPH General - Medical Education, 1950-1957 (Box 63, Folder 577)
    - DMPH General - Medical Education - Documents, 1951-1953; 11 items (Box 63, Folder 578)
    - DMPH General - Nursing Former Fellows, 1948, 1954-1955 (Box 63, Folder 579)
    - DMPH General - Preventive Medicine, 1951-1954 (Box 63, Folder 580)
    - DMPH General - Program and Policy, 1951-1956 (Box 63, Folder 581)
    - DMPH General - Psychobiological Development of the Child - (World Health Organization Study Group), 1952-1954 (Box 63, Folder 582)
    - DMPH General - Retarded Children - (schools or centers for), 1954-1955 (Box 63, Folder 583)
    - DMPH General - Ricardo Prime Mover, 1953-1954 (Box 63, Folder 584)
    - DMPH General - Rome Office, 1951-1955 (Box 63, Folder 585)
    - DMPH General - Sanitary Engineering, 1951-1956 (Box 63, Folder 586)
    - DMPH General - Virus Program, 1952-1955 (Box 63, Folder 587)
    - DMPH General - World Federation for Mental Health, 1951-1954 (Box 64, Folder 588)
    - DMPH General - World Health Organization, 1951-1955 (Box 64, Folder 589)
    - DMPH General - World Health Organization - European Office, 1951-1956 (Box 64, Folder 590)
    - DMPH General - World Health Organization - Insect Control, 1951-1952 (Box 64, Folder 591)
    - DMPH General - World Health Organization - Malaria Epidemiology, 1951-1955 (Box 64, Folder 592)
    - DMPH General - World Health Organization - Mental Health, 1952-1955 (Box 64, Folder 593)
    - DMPH General - World Health Organization - Nursing, 1951-1957 (Box 64, Folder 594)
    - DMPH General - World Health Organization - Personnel Training Section, 1950-1954 (Box 64, Folder 595)
    - DMPH General - World Health Organization - Sanitary Engineering, 1949-1955 (Box 64, Folder 596)
      Bouty, H.G. - 1951-1954 Pavanello, Renato - 1952-1955 Schaafsma, N. D. R. - 1949-1950 Sundry Letters - 1951-1954
    - General - American Hospital, 1949-1955 (Box 64, Folder 597)
    - General - Auditing, 1949-1954 (Box 64, Folder 598)
    - General - Belgian American Educational Foundation, 1944-1945 (Box 64, Folder 599)
    - General - Books and Publication - Gifts, 1949-1959 (Box 65, Folder 600)
    - General - Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, 1954-1958 (Box 65, Folder 601)
    - General - Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique - Supplementary Material, 1950-1958; 7 items (Box 65, Folder 602)
    - General - Cite Universitaire, 1948-1959 (Box 65, Folder 603)
    - General - College de l'Europe Libre, 1954-1957 (Box 65, Folder 604)
    - General - Comite International d'Aide aux Intellectuels, 1952-1954 (Box 65, Folder 605)
    - General - Commission Franco-Americain d'Echanges Universitaires, 1957-1958 (Box 65, Folder 606)
    - General - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1955-1958 (Box 65, Folder 607)
    - General - Customs - Importation of Equipment, 1938-1955 (Box 65, Folder 608)
    - General - Czechoslovakian Grants, 1947 (Box 65, Folder 609)
    - General - Declinations, 1950-1959 (Box 65, Folder 610)
    - General - Declinations - Lists, 1956-1958 (Box 65, Folder 611)
    - General - European Research Groups, 1950 (Box 65, Folder 612)
    - General - Fehling, August Wilhelm - (book purchase), 1948-1953 (Box 65, Folder 613)
    - General - Fellowship Directory, 1949-1954 (Box 65, Folder 614)
    - General - Fellowship Directory IHD, 1950-1951 (Box 66, Folder 615)
    - General - Finland Grants, Miscellaneous Lists (Box 66, Folder 616)
    - General - Ford Foundation, 1952-1954 (Box 66, Folder 617)
    - General - Foundation Singer-Palignac report, 1958 (Box 66, Folder 618)
    - General - Franco-Polish University Committee, 1957 (Box 66, Folder 619)
    - General - French Welcome Organization for World Medical Corps, 1949 (Box 66, Folder 620)
    - General - Germany Miscellaneous, 1949-1953 (Box 66, Folder 621)
      German Research Council - 1949 Max Planck Society - 1949 Cultural exchange with U.S. - 1953
    - General - Germany - RF grants to, 1945-1953 (Box 66, Folder 622)
    - General - Germany - Higher Education in, 1952-1953 (Box 66, Folder 623)
    - General - Germany - Investigations in, 1945 (Box 66, Folder 624)
    - General - Hungary - Miscellaneous, 1947-1958 (Box 66, Folder 625)
      Domanousky, A. - Hungarian Scholarships Council - 1947 Fischelis, Robert L. - Columbia University Research Project - 1958
    - General - Institut National d'Etudes - Demographiques, 1942-1954 (Box 66, Folder 626)
    - General - International Union for Conservation of Nature, 1957-1958 (Box 66, Folder 627)
    - General - Kimball, Lindsley F. - (general correspondence), 1949-1959 (Box 66, Folder 628)
    - General - Laugier, Henri - (physiology), 1950, 1951, 1957 (Box 66, Folder 629)
    - General - Miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 630)
    - General - Mouvement Europeen - "Nouvelles de l'Europe", 1955 (Box 66, Folder 631)
    - General - Makinsky, Alexandre - (general correspondence), 1944-1957 (Box 66, Folder 632)
    - General - Nansen Haus - (international student house), 1949-1952 (Box 66, Folder 633)
    - General - Netherlands Foundation Man and Community, 1957-1958 (Box 67, Folder 634)
    - General - Paris Office - Equipment and Purchases, 1947-1954 (Box 67, Folder 635)
    - General - Paris Office - Financial, 1944-1954 (Box 67, Folder 636)
    - General - Paris Office - Maintenance, 1954-1959 (Box 67, Folder 637)
    - General - Paris Office - Personnel, 1945-1952 (Box 67, Folder 638)
    - General - Paris Office - Remodeling, 1955-1956 (Box 67, Folder 639)
    - General - Paris Office - Remodeling - Estimates and Payments, 1955-1956 (Box 67, Folder 640)
    - General - Paris Office - Rent, Heating charges, 1946-1955 (Box 67, Folder 641)
    - General - Paris Office, 1945-1958 (Box 67, Folder 642)
      Telephone Contracts and Invoices - 1945-1958 resale - 1955
    - General - Pasteur Institute, 1945-1958 (Box 67, Folder 643)
    - General - Poland - Correspondence relayed (from New York), 1958-1959 (Box 67, Folder 644)
    - General - Poland - Miscellaneous (list of fellows) (Box 67, Folder 645)
    - General - Population Problems, 1949-1957 (Box 67, Folder 646)
    - General - Procedure - Financial, 1947-1957 (Box 67, Folder 647)
    - General - Psychologists - European, 1953 (Box 68, Folder 648)
    - General - Relief Organizations, 1948 (Box 68, Folder 649)
    - General - Rockefeller Brothers, 1954-1958 (Box 68, Folder 650)
    - General - Rockefeller Foundation - Miscellaneous Correspondence - Visitors, 1946-1958 (Box 68, Folder 651)
    - General - Rockefeller Foundation - Post-war European Activities, 1945-1949, 1950 (Box 68, Folder 652)
    - General - Rockefeller Foundation - Research aid statements, 1931-1946 (Box 68, Folder 653)
    - General - Royal Tropical Institute (Amsterdam), 1958 (Box 68, Folder 654)
    - General - Sale of Sixth Floor - (Paris office), 1955-1956 (Box 68, Folder 655)
    - General - Salzburg Seminar - (American studies), 1947-1956 (Box 68, Folder 656)
    - General - Shipping papers, 1952-1954 (Box 68, Folder 657)
    - General - Social Policy and the Social Sciences - Conferences, 1953 (Box 68, Folder 658)
    - General - Social Policy and the Social Sciences - Conferences - Reports (3 v.), 1953 (Box 68, Folder 659)
    - General - Societe Immobiliere La Baume-Haussman, 1942-1959 (Box 69, Folder 660)
    - General - Societe Immobiliere La Baume-Haussman, 1942-1959 (Box 69, Folder 661)
    - General - Societe Immobiliere La Baume-Haussman, 1942-1959 (Box 69, Folder 662)
    - General - Societe Immobiliere La Baume-Haussman, 1942-1959 (Box 69, Folder 663)
    - General - Sundry Requests, 1953-1958 (Box 69, Folder 664)
    - General - Travel-Staff Members, 1953-1957 (Box 69, Folder 665)
    - General - Twentieth Century Fund, 1956 (Box 69, Folder 666)
    - General - UNESCO - general, 1952-1958 (Box 69, Folder 667)
    - General - Unitarian Service Committee, Inc., 1948-1957 (Box 69, Folder 668)
    - General - United Nations High Commission for Refugees, 1951-1954 (Box 69, Folder 669)
    - General - U.S.R.O. - (united States Regional Organizations), 1955 (Box 69, Folder 670)
    - General - Yugoslavia - Miscellaneous, 1951-1953 (Box 69, Folder 671)
  - Post-war - Financial Material, 02
    - Account Book, 1936-1956 (Box 70, Folder 672)
    - Account Book, 1948-1950 (Box 70, Folder 673)
    - Account Book, 1950-1952 (Box 70, Folder 674)
    - Account Books (6), 1952-1958 (Box 70, Folder 675)
    - Account Books (6), 1955-1957 (Box 70, Folder 676)
    - Dollar Account - Statements, Correspondence, 1955-1958 (Box 70, Folder 677)
    - Group Insurance and Retirement - Correspondence, Policies, Receipts, 1951-1959 (Box 70, Folder 678)
    - Insurance Policies (3), 1942-1949 (Box 71, Folder 679)
    - Payroll, 1948-1959 (Box 71, Folder 680)
    - Payroll Check Vouchers, 1955-1959 (Box 71, Folder 681)
    - Salary Account Book, 1947-1958 (Box 71, Folder 682)
    - Salary Tax, 1948-1953 (Box 71, Folder 683)
    - Social Security, 1947-1953 (Box 71, Folder 684)
    - Societe Immobiliere La Baume-Haussman - (Office Space, Leases, Receipts, Correspondence), 1942-1954 (Box 71, Folder 685)
    - Debit Vouchers - Francs, 1949-1951 (Box 72, Folder data_value_missing_3b0e5dba7afbfcb4a817a9e193988f87)
    - Debit Vouchers - Francs, 1952-1954 (Box 73, Folder data_value_missing_2efbeffd38e16db018e8eedc94d6e119)
    - Debit Vouchers - Francs, 1955-1959 (June) (Box 74, Folder data_value_missing_1e13c071844992702acac61c7f347b40)
    - Debit Vouchers - Dollars, 1949-1950 (Box 74, Folder data_value_missing_319b52ede9b9b2b1a4dfad15d3d337df)
    - Debit Vouchers - Dollars, 1951-1954 (Box 75, Folder data_value_missing_1de9cf54736624333df9f636fe5d0f6c)
    - Petty Cash Vouchers - Dollars, 1952-1954 (Box 75, Folder data_value_missing_59fa4adb356dd40f1b1637c2e3085cd4)
    - Petty Cash Vouchers - Francs, 1952 (Box 75, Folder data_value_missing_72fbc44e93bf56f1b495496fd43eb7ac)
    - Petty Cash Vouchers - Francs, 1953-1959 (June) (Box 76, Folder data_value_missing_13273cebbb6d455618b9f04887006732)
    - Chase National Bank (dollars) - Cheque Book Stubs No. 1 to No. 7 incl., January 1947 - June 21, 1951 (Box 77, Folder data_value_missing_506175cde5df7a783587ca9638704379)
    - Chase National Bank (dollars) - Cheque Book Stubs No. 8 to No. 13 incl., June 21, 1951 - April 30, 1954 (Box 78, Folder data_value_missing_cbeafb741fc967a6c46b4640435df1f9)
    - Chase National Bank (Francs) - Cheque Book Stubs No. 1 to No. 45 incl., January 5, 1945 - November 30, 1951 (Box 79, Folder data_value_missing_3a0b393e06793ed8494f5a73c152dc72)
    - Chase National Bank (Francs) - Cheque Book Stubs No. 46 to No. 62 incl., November 30, 1951 - April 30, 1954 (Box 80, Folder data_value_missing_52e9783fa39a735dd88a0e0310c97948)
    - Chase National Bank (Francs) - Cheque Book Stubs No. 1 to No. 12 incl., January 5, 1954 - March 27, 1959 (Box 81, Folder data_value_missing_2d0020086d2dd8f6c195d26a60fde12c)
    - Ledger 12 (Volume Ledger 12)
    - Ledger 13 (Volume Ledger 13)
    - Ledger 14 (Volume Ledger 14)
    - Ledger 15 (Volume Ledger 15)
    - Ledger 16 (Volume Ledger 16)
    - Ledger 17 (Volume Ledger 17)
    - Ledger 18 (Volume Ledger 18)
    - Ledger 19 (Volume Ledger 19)
    - Ledger 20 (Volume Ledger 20)
    - Ledger 21 (Volume Ledger 21)
    - Ledger 22 (Volume Ledger 22)